# Hui Ye

#### Research Focus

My research interests lie in the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and Computer Graphics (CG). Specifically, my main research focus is on exploring novel mobile AR prototyping tools and techniques for 3D contents and interactions.

#### Education

• City University of Hong Kong (CityU)

Sep 2017-Aug 2022

Ph.D. in Creative Media Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

Thesis: 3D Content and Interaction Prototyping with Mobile Augmented Reality

• University of Science and Technology of China (USTC)

Sep 2012-June 2016

B.A. in Communication

Minor in Computer Science and Technology

### Experience

• RGC Postdoctoral Fellow, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2022-Current

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Research Assistant, City University of Hong Kong

Sep 2021-Aug 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Hongbo Fu

• Visiting Ph.D. student, Tsinghua University

Dec 2019-Apr 2020

Institute of HCI and Media Integration Advisors: Dr. Chun Yu and Prof. Hongbo Fu

• City University of Hong Kong

Sep-Dec 2014

Exchange student

#### **Publications**

- Hui Ye, Jiaye Leng (joint first author), Pengfei Xu, Karan Singh and Hongbo Fu. 2023. ProInterAR:
   A Visual Programming Platform for Creating Immersive AR Interactions. In *Proceedings of the 2024 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2024).
- **Hui Ye**, Jiaye Leng, Chufeng Xiao, Lili Wang and Hongbo Fu. 2023. ProObjAR: Prototyping Spatially-aware Interactions of Smart Objects with AR-HMD. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2023).
- Hui Ye and Hongbo Fu. 2022. ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-world IoT Enhanced Spaces. In *Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI 2022).
- **Hui Ye**, Kin Chung Kwan, and Hongbo Fu. 2021. 3D Curve Creation on and around Physical Objects with Mobile AR. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG)*.
- Hui Ye, Kin Chung Kwan (joint first author), Wanchao Su, and Hongbo Fu. 2020. ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures. In ACM Transactions on Graphics (Special Issue of ACM SIGGRAPH 2020).

- o Wanchao Su, **Hui Ye**, Shuyu Chen, Lin Gao, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. DrawingInStyles: Portrait Image Generation and Editing with Spatially Conditioned StyleGAN. In *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics* (*TVCG*).
- Xuanyu Wang, Hui Ye, Christian Sandor, Weizhan Zhang, and Hongbo Fu. 2022. Predict-and-Drive: Avatar Motion Adaption in Room-Scale Augmented Reality Telepresence with Heterogeneous Spaces. In IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG): Special Issue for IEEE ISMAR 2022.
- Yanxiang Zhang and **Hui Ye**. 2016. Time-Based Nonlinear Interactive Player. In *International Conference on Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality and Computer Graphics*. Springer, Cham.
- Yanxiang Zhang, Yun Zhu, **Hui Ye**. 2015. The Design of an Augmented Reality Based Rigid Body Motion Experiment System. In *Applied Mechanics and Materials*. Trans Tech Publications Ltd.

# **Selected Honors & Awards**

	2022
Science and Technology Progress Award of Anhui (Third Prize)	2023
• RGC Postdoctoral Fellowship	2022
Outstanding Academic Performance Award of CityU	2021
Shidi CAD&CG Excellent Student Award	2021
Research Tuition Scholarship of CityU	2020
<ul> <li>Guo Moruo Scholarship (Top 1.7%, Highest Honor for USTC Undergraduates)</li> </ul>	2016
<ul> <li>Merit Graduate of Anhui Province &amp; USTC (Top 3%)</li> </ul>	2016
<ul> <li>Certificate of Honorary Rank of USTC (Top 5%)</li> </ul>	2016
<ul> <li>Outstanding Thesis of USTC</li> </ul>	2016
<ul> <li>Sun Bin Leadership Scholarship of USTC</li> </ul>	2014
<ul> <li>Aegon-Industrial Responsibility Scholarship of USTC</li> </ul>	2014
<ul> <li>Outstanding Instructor in "Science and Technology Week" of USTC</li> </ul>	2013-15
<ul> <li>Gold Award of Excellent Student Scholarship of USTC (Top 5%)</li> </ul>	2013
<ul> <li>Outstanding Young Volunteer of USTC</li> </ul>	2013
Talks	
<ul> <li>The Road from Communication to Computer Graphics Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&amp;CG 2022+2023</li> </ul>	Aug 2022
• •	Aug 2022 May 2022
Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&CG 2022+2023  • ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces	Ü
<ul> <li>Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&amp;CG 2022+2023</li> <li>ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces         Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022     </li> <li>Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions</li> </ul>	May 2022
<ul> <li>Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&amp;CG 2022+2023</li> <li>ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces         Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022     </li> <li>Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions         Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute     </li> <li>Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents and Interactions         SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward     </li> <li>ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined Motion Gestures</li> </ul>	May 2022 Apr 2022 Dec 2021
<ul> <li>Invited Presenter, Student Colloquium, CAD&amp;CG 2022+2023</li> <li>ProGesAR: Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions with Real-worldIoT Enhanced Spaces         Conference Paper Presenter, CHI 2022     </li> <li>Mobile AR Prototyping for Proxemic and Gestural Interactions         Invited Speaker, EAA Youth Academic Forum, Tianjin Fine Arts Institute     </li> <li>Exploring Novel Mobile AR Prototyping Techniques and Tools for 3D Contents and Interactions         SIGGRAPH Thesis Fast Forward     </li> <li>ARAnimator: In-situ Character Animation in Mobile AR with User-defined</li> </ul>	May 2022 Apr 2022

# o In-situ 3D Content Creation in Mobile AR

Mar 2021

Invited Speaker, Affiliated Forum on Human, Technology and Future of IWHEC 2021

# **Teaching Experience**

o Teaching Assistant, CityU SM1103A Introduction to Media Computing

2018 & 19 Fall

o Teaching Assistant, CityU SM2716 Physical Computing & Tangible Media

2018 Spring

# **Professional Service**

 Program Committees: CSCW 2023-24, SIGGRAPH Asia Emerging Technologies 2024, UbiComp/ISWC Notes and Briefs 2024, CHI Late-Breaking Work 2023-24, CHI Student Research Competition 2022

Paper Reviewing

Special Recognition for Outstanding Reviews CHI, CSCW, MobileHCI

Conference: SIGGRAPH 2024, SIGGRAPH Asia 2022-23, CHI 2020/22/23/24, PG 2020/23, UIST 2022, MobileHCI 2022, IEEE VR 2021, IEEE AIVR 2021

Journal: ACM TOG, IEEE TVCG, IEEE TMC, IEEE C&G, IEEE CG&A, The Visual Computer

• Student Helper: PG 2018

### Skills

o **Programming Language**: C#, Swift, Python, JavaScript

o Graphics Interface: OpenCV, QT

o Application Tools: iOS App, ARKit, HoloLens, Mixed Reality Toolkit

o Hardware: HoloLens, Arduino, Motion Capture

Last updated on March 25, 2023